Duty is sacrifice.
It eclipses all
things. even blood.
All men of honor
must pay its price.
The North owes a great
duty to the Seven Kingdoms.
One older than any oath.
Since the days of the First
Men. we have stood as guardians
against the cold and the dark.
Through its long tradition.
the Night's Watch cultivated
its strength from doomed men
who had their life as
their only possession.
But my ancestor. Torrhen Stark.
began a tradition by making an
offering at the onset of winter:
one in 10 men from our household was
to be chosen to fortify the Watch.
This is not a
sentence but an honor.
A duty embraced by all
who serve the North.
Even by mine own kin.
The North must stand ready.
Winter is coming.
Coming? What is this. then.
that falls from the skies
and shivers my bones?
This is only a late
summer snow. my prince.
In winter. it will
cover all you see.
and all memories of
warmth will be forgotten.
It pleases me to think
that over a century ago
our ancestors treated
in this very place.
The Conqueror and the
King in the North.
You. at least. had the mercy not
to threaten me with your dragon.
My prince.
- My lord.
M'lord.
Surely the great Torrhen Stark would've
sooner died than bent the knee.
Unless he believed the Conqueror could
bring unity to the Seven Kingdoms.
You are right in that.
That unity is now threatened.
The realm will soon
tear itself apart
if men do not remember the
oath sworn to King Viserys
and to his rightful heir.
Starks do not forget
their oaths. my prince.
But you must know that my gaze is
forever torn between north and south.
In winter. my duty to the
Wall is even more dire
than the one I owe
to King's Landing.
I need my men here.
Whilst your men guard against
wildlings and weather.
the Hightowers plan
to usurp the throne.
If my mother is to defend her
claim to hold the realm united.
she needs an army.
War is coming
to the whole of
the realm. my lord.
We cannot wage it without
the support of the North.
My father brought King Jaehaerys
and Queen Alysanne to see the Wall.
His Grace stood at this very outlook
and watched as their dragons.
the greatest power in the
world. refused to cross it.
Do you think my ancestors
built a 700-foot wall of ice
to keep out snow and savages?
What does it keep out?
Death.
I have thousands of graybeards
who've already seen too many winters.
They are well-honed.
So they're old?
I can ready them
to march at once.
If your graybeards can fight.
the queen will have them.
They will fight hard.
Like Northerners.
My lord?
A raven's arrived.
Urgent news from Dragonstone.
Take your mount again.
We're flying out.
I alone patrol over a
hundred miles of open sea.
endlessly. to hold the blockade.
Meleys must gorge
and rest. as must I.
- We're going to King's Landing.
- To what end?
Killing Vhagar. I cannot face
that hoary old bitch alone.
With my dragon and yours together.
we can kill Vhagar and her rider.
Make it a son for a son.
- Was this the queen's command?
- The queen remains absent.
I should be at
Harrenhal bending knees.
but I must instead remain
here to wage her war.
Or perhaps. more simply.
to await her return.
She has been gone for days.
Too long. She is exposed.
- She is grieving.
- The mother grieves
as the queen shirks her duties.
It was a raven that brought
me news of Laena's death.
I existed for weeks in torment
refusing to believe
what I'd been told.
It was only when I saw my
daughter's mortal remains
that I could begin to mourn her.
A raven has told Rhaenyra
that her son is dead.
She needs to know
it for certain.
She was a fool to go alone.
What if Aemond were
to happen upon her?
Then I would pity Aemond.
The queen was wise
to recuse herself.
She has not acted on the vengeful
impulse that others might have.
If you'd have acted
when you had the chance.
Aegon's line would
be extinguished.
And Luke would be alive.
Fly with me.
- It is a command.
- Would that you were the king.
M'lord.
It's a marvel she was able to
return from the Stepstones at all.
Barely done. but done.
Seven more ships put out to sea
this morn' to fortify the blockade.
The Gullet is vast. and we're
not like to have the numbers
to cover all that open water.
I must have my ship back
at sea to lead the effort.
It'll be many weeks
yet. I'd wager.
But I'll have a
word with my brother
to see what reinforcements
the shipwrights can muster.
The smithy delivered
this earlier.
M'lord?
I had this commissioned
for Prince Lucerys.
I was very sorry to hear
about your heir's death.
'Twas the blackest
of treacheries.
Pardon. m'lord. if it'll
please you. much to do.
They tell me that you are the one
that dragged my body out of the sea.
It was only my duty.
I am indebted to you. Alyn.
Mind your posts!
Keep your focus. men!
- Dragon!
Arm the scorpion!
Approaching from the southeast!
Get around!
Scorpion ready!
- Halt!
Stand down. it's Vhagar!
Stand down!
Standing down!
Where is Jaehaerys?
Attending his lessons.
And those are where?
What do you need of him?
Taking him to the small council.
He'll be king one day. He
must begin his instruction.
What if he does not
want to be king?
Where is he?
The library.
You must not
interrupt his custom.
I'm afraid.
Don't be.
They'd be fools to come with
Vhagar protecting the city.
Not the dragons.
The rats.
The queen is an
enduring mystery.
is she not?
There's a chill in the air.
Summer is well
and truly through.
We are expected at the
small council. Your Grace.
We cannot.
Again.
Yes. Your Grace.
If you wouldn't mind?
- Your Grace.
- Good day.
Hello! Jaehaerys must
learn the ways of the court
if he is to rule one day.
Up we go.
Good morrow. my lords.
Mother.
What news?
Our letters to the Vale and to the
North continue to go unanswered.
Cunts.
The Stormlands should be ours
after Prince Aemond's marriage pact
to the Lady Floris Baratheon.
I anticipate their
sworn declaration.
My brother is raising
the strength of the West
to mass at the Golden
Tooth. but we...
Yeah. thank you. my prince.
That's very helpful.
My nephew. Lord Ormund.
musters his forces to
sally forth from Oldtown.
They expect to march quickly.
meeting little resistance.
until they reach the Riverlands.
My letters to Rhaenyra.
Has there been any answer?
An apology for her dead son?
None. Your Grace.
Between that and their
blockade of the Gullet.
we must presume that
the princess has refused
the offered terms
and that war is now inevitable.
Perhaps Your Grace might lend
- his voice to our outreach...
- Stop! Enough!
in hopes that new terms
might be negotiated.
Release it at once!
Would someone please?
Is the heir to the throne
bothering you. Tyland?
No. No. no. not in
the least. Your Grace.
Because I think he wants a ride.
- Your Grace.
- A ride?
A pony ride.
Wouldn't that be fun. Jaehaerys?
Should the Master of
Coin be your royal steed?
Your Grace!
There are important
matters to discuss
despite Sir Tyland's
interruptions.
Very well.
No time for amusements. Tyland.
Your Grace.
Off you go. Jaehaerys. Good boy.
Where were we?
Rhaenyra's blockade has placed
King's Landing under strain.
And those pressures
will multiply quickly.
Well. we should've just killed
her when we had the chance.
Regrettably. the opportunity
for surprise has been lost
and. with it. the chance to
end this conflict quickly.
We must play the
board before us.
If we are to break the
Sea Snake's blockade.
we will need to bolster both the
Lannister and Hightower navies.
We do have need for a
new Master of Ships.
We could offer the title to
the young Lord Dalton Greyjoy.
Aemond. What is
your business here?
The king summoned me.
You do not have a
seat at this council.
Aemond is my closest
blood and our best sword.
I welcome him.
Path to King's Landing is
through the Riverlands.
We must establish a toehold
there. at Harrenhal.
The Riverlords will
either declare for me
or they will meet Vhagar
and Sunfyre together.
And we can burn the
blockade while we're at it.
- Rhaenyra has dragons as well.
- Mine are bigger.
If we lose the dragons to war.
there'll be no calling them back.
- We must proceed cautiously.
- No.
Fat. old Lord Tully will either
raise my banner or see his burn.
We should fly to Riverrun.
You are the king. Your Grace. You
must not put yourself at risk.
And Vhagar is needed here to
deter Rhaenyra from attacking
in retribution for
the death of her son.
Errors were made in the hours
following King Viserys's death.
We mustn't compound them.
You've already demonstrated
your might. Your Grace.
We must now favor
patience and restraint.
I send ravens by the hour.
Many and more houses will
declare for you in time.
History and precedent
will come to your side.
Good morrow. Your Grace.
Good morrow. Lord Larys.
I had come earlier to have a word
before the small council convened.
but your handmaiden said
that you were indisposed.
What is it you wish to discuss?
I have completed questioning
the whole of the castle staff.
They produced rather
interesting details
but I am satisfied I have exposed
all who betrayed our trust.
And what of them?
They no longer breathe our air.
I have chosen your
new staff personally.
Give me that.
Your Grace?
Just leave me.
- It's a dragon wing!
- Let's have a look!
- It's a wing.
- Who cares what it is.
Dragon!
All hail King Aegon!
"Aegon the Magnanimous."
Second of His Name. King of the Andals.
and the Rhoynar. and the First Men.
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms.
and Protector of the Realm.
Hail King Aegon!
"The Magnanimous"?
Your Grace.
Let's have the first
petition. my good Lord Hand.
Good morrow. my... Your Grace.
It's alright. There's
no reason to be nervous.
What's your name?
Gr... Jerard. Your Grace.
Good morrow. Jerard. And how
might your king be of service?
'Tis my flock.
A tenth of them taken by
the Crown on. on
the cusp of winter.
- If I'd had the time to plan...
- We should return them.
Your Grace?
Well. you need your goats
for the winter. don't you?
- Sheep. Your Grace.
- Sheep. even better.
I shall make your
flock of sheep whole.
We already made a promise
to all the Crownlands
that a tithing of livestock would
be necessary to sustain the dragons
for their increased activity
and. pray not. eventual fighting.
Right. Right.
Perhaps we could just return
his sheep. He came all this way.
If you return one herder's
sheep. Your Grace.
you will soon find them all
at the foot of your throne
expecting the same.
They won't know.
When the king speaks.
Your Grace. all hear it.
After further thought. I have decided
that I cannot restore your sheep.
If war were to break out. my
dragons will require feed.
Bring the next.
Salts always run scarce
on the road to winter.
Your Grace.
We rely on ships from
Essos for our supply.
But now. with a blockade in
place and war threatening...
Yeah. that treasonous
blockade won't last long.
I plan to send Vhagar
to burn it to ash.
Bring the next.
Hugh. Your Grace.
The smiths are all proud to support
Your Grace against Rhaenyra.
But?
But...
iron costs have grown.
A lone scorpion
takes weeks to build.
To put it simply.
we are struggling.
If we could but have the Crown's
coin before we started work.
it would bring great relief.
Not just to me. but to all
the smiths serving your cause.
You shall be paid and paid well.
My army cannot win a war
without your weapons.
You should continue
their making.
Our victory depends on the
efforts of the smallfolk.
You have my most sincere
gratitude. Your Grace.
I'll hear the next petition.
Your Grace. it filled my heart
to see you on the Iron Throne.
I was only a boy when
Jaehaerys last graced the seat.
but you brought forth
memories of him.
and you have such a deft
touch with the smallfolk.
just as your father did.
Thank you. my lord.
I wonder. do you have a
moment for a quiet word?
It is the Hand's wont to
keep a firm grip on things.
He controlled your
father the same way.
Viserys had a certain
reputation as being pliable.
I am aware.
I would think. as
we find ourselves
standing within a
hair's breadth of war.
that you would wish to
be viewed differently.
How?
Otto Hightower
was your father's
Hand. Your Grace.
Daughter.
I requested an
audience hours ago.
There were many petitions.
I find myself wondering.
do we pursue the same end?
I must admit. there are days
where I myself can't be sure.
I shall tell you mine.
It's victory.
And how would you
define "victory"?
Rhaenyra bending the knee
and Aegon sitting the
Iron Throne. in peace.
As Viserys wished.
Well. if that's how you describe
it. then we are aligned.
- Then be my ally.
- I am.
An ally would not repeatedly cut my legs
from beneath me at that table of men!
- I sit there and I feel your anger.
- Frustration.
These critical days
since Viserys's passing
- haven't gone to plan.
- That's not my fault.
My sons both see you
as the great example.
The Hand to three kings.
Aegon is ever-eager to
prove himself and Aemond...
Aemond is angry.
Rhaenyra's son took his eye
and was never punished for it.
- What he did. however vicious...
- The caprice of youth.
I could only hope.
Aemond erred.
But he is fiercely loyal.
He wishes to please.
And Aegon still heeds
me. In private. at least.
But if you undermine my voice. both
those boys will grow deaf to it.
I hadn't seen it that way.
We only need to mind Aegon until
the novelty of rule is spent.
Once he tires of it. you and I
can steer our cause to victory.
A fine strategy. daughter.
But you must accept that the path
to victory now is one of violence.
I know it.
But that does not mean
it must be wanton.
No.
Prepare to be boarded!
By the order of Lord
Corlys Velaryon!
Search the hold for stowaways!
You.
When last we met.
there were two of you.
"The White Worm."
Did you think I would
wither in your absence?
I did not think you
would flower a traitor.
You speak of highborn
games. I am common-born.
How long have you been selling
secrets to Otto Hightower?
As long as he had
gold to pay for them.
Who sent you fleeing from King's
Landing in such disrepair. hm?
You put Aegon on the throne.
That was the
Hightowers' conspiracy.
I merely profited from
knowing Aegon's movements.
But you delivered him.
He would've returned home
eventually for gold and for respite.
as he always does.
I simply. simply sped
the business along.
"Business" that ended with the
theft of the queen's throne
and the murder of her son.
You only blame me
because your true enemies
are out of reach.
My arrangement with the Hand
was purely transactional.
I held no loyalty to him.
Certainly do not now.
Otto Hightower was to me
as I am to your noble ilk.
fodder to be cast off.
What else do you know
of him? His plans?
Little and less.
I possess nothing of
value to you. Daemon.
Have her moved to the cells.
She is to be treated as
a traitor to the crown.
Forgive me. my prince. but
the lady speaks the truth.
- She was no agent of the Hightowers.
- What is it to you?
- A matter of honor.
- Was it honor that made you stand by
and watch as the Hightowers
usurped the throne?
You and your traitorous twin.
No. my prince.
I'm shamed by it.
That's why I abandoned the Kingsguard.
and my brother. and came here.
I don't care.
Aegon was in your grasp. You
should've killed him yourself.
Arryk and I were named to the
Kingsguard at just 8 and 10.
And we swore the same oath: to
defend the whole of the royal family.
So what were we to do when they
turned against one another?
Queen Rhaenyra Targaryen.
the First of Her Name.
Queen of the Andals. and the
Rhoynar. and the First Men.
Lady of the Seven Kingdoms.
and Protector of the Realm.
Did you find what you needed?
Your council stands at
the ready. Your Grace.
I will fly to Harrenhal at your command
and set our toehold in the Riverlands.
Your Grace. my lord husband's
blockade of the Gullet
moves into place.
All seaborne travel and trade to
King's Landing will soon be cut off.
I want Aemond Targaryen.
In your years as a
merchant of gossip.
you surely accumulated
spies within the Red Keep.
Servants who knew the
comings and goings.
Scheme with someone
else. Daemon.
I was once in your
thrall. but no longer.
A transaction. then.
Your knowledge in
exchange for your freedom.
Your Grace.
Lady Jeyne Arryn has
pledged her support
in exchange for a dragon
to guard the Vale.
And Lord Cregan Stark
has promised 2.000 men...
Alyrie Florent.
Viserys Targaryen.
Lucerys Velaryon.
A tribute.
Commander?
Never gone for long.
I'm told you bear a
mislike for the Hightowers.
Fuck the Hightowers.
Keep walking.
Don't make trouble.
The White Worm said you're
one of Aegon's ratcatchers.
You must be busy.
That castle positively
crawls with them now.
I heard the White
Worm were dead.
Her ghost told me you
were a betting man.
Fighting pits?
Dogs. and bones.
How deep are your debts?
I was also given to
understand that you possess
a unique knowledge
of the Red Keep.
Maegor's tunnels.
Great big rat's nest. it is.
I know them better than
the shape of my own cock.
This is my friend.
Tonight. he's going
to be your friend.
You're to find and slay the
Prince Aemond Targaryen.
He has silver hair and one eye.
Should be easy enough to find.
But I understand he's
quite good in a fight.
You'll want to take caution.
That's one half. You'll get
the other when it's done.
Alright.
What if we can't find him?
We've wasted precious days in
this war of quills and ravens.
Words are wind.
You should be leading the van
and I should be flying
cover on Vhagar.
No castle would dare to raise
Rhaenyra's banner against us.
We would bring the whole of the
Crownlands to heel in weeks.
Well. mayhaps we could
petition the king.
privately. to send us out.
Rosby and Stokeworth.
small castles right in the
shadow of King's Landing.
They would not want
us for enemies.
We could add their
levies to our own.
Our host growing as we advance.
It is a canny scheme.
But moot.
My brother is hostage to
my grandsire and mother
and they tell him that a war
of dragons can yet be avoided.
'Tis inevitable.
They must see that.
Otto fears to upset
the order of things.
And Alicent is simply...
angry.
- Angry?
- She blames me for starting this war
after she plotted with my father's
council to usurp his throne.
"Her Grace" speaks
with two tongues.
She has a gentle heart.
And Rhaenyra is
a cunning spider.
Long ago. she drew
Alicent into her web.
intoxicated her.
It is not your mother's fault.
She holds love for our enemy.
That makes her a fool.
Lord Hand.
Return to your post.
Lord Commander.
I must have a word
with the prince.
It would concern me. grandson.
if plans were being considered beyond
the ears of your king and his Hand.
You have a zeal to
act. I understand.
I was young once myself...
I only wish to serve
my king and my house.
You and Vhagar
are the greatest single
power in the realm.
If it wasn't obvious
before. it certainly is now.
But there are many
pieces at play here
some of which you can't yet see.
I promise you. Aemond. you will
have all the vengeance that you seek
but you must keep a
grip on your impulses.
We both know that
your brother cannot.
Alright.
Take that.
Bring the dog.
I need to be a symbol
for the smallfolk.
- as well as the nobility.
- Wait.
You could always be
"Aegon the Strong."
My nephew's already
taken that one.
Well. which would
Your Grace prefer?
- It's the king.
- To be loved or feared?
I need to be both.
My mother and grandsire mind
me like some helpless duckling.
Oh. well. you're the king. Who
gives a shit what they say?
My brother. at least.
knows his place.
He's as loyal as a hound.
I can set him and his
dragon on my foes at will.
- Keep your eyes down.
- I need a style that
demonstrates power
and commands respect.
No one knows what
"magnanimous" means.
You could be "Aegon
the Generous" then.
- That would charm the smallfolk.
- I like that.
Is there more strong wine?
- "Aegon the Dragonheart."
- Better.
"Aegon the Dragoncock!"
Yes. yes! Yeah. the
untamable beast!
How do we get upstairs?
The royals live up there.
Right.
Well. it's off limits. it is.
Different group of
ratcatchers work the upstairs.
If we're to kill a royal fucking prince.
where do you think we're gonna find him?
I got you in the castle.
I thought the rest was your bit.
I could end you right here. take
the rest of the gold meself.
I know a way upstairs. I just
don't know my way 'round.
Show me.
Fuck off.
This way.
The royals live on this level.
No one's here.
We need to keep looking.
I've told ya. I'm not
supposed to be up here.
Did you not hear the prince?
No head. no gold.
Set a trap.
For appearances.
I'll search the next room.
For the rats.
Quiet.
Stay still.
Who the fuck is she?
She's the queen. she is.
"A son for a son." he said.
Well. does she look like
a fucking son to you?
Over there.
We need to get our
head and get out.
They both look the same.
Which one's the boy?
- Maybe that one.
- Well. look for a cock.
The mother knows.
Do anything but what I ask. and
I'll bleed the whole lot of ya.
Which?
I have a necklace.
It's of great value.
That's not a son.
Wait.
It's the other one.
She's not gonna give up
the king's heir that easy.
No.
She's telling true.
Hold him down.
No.
Helaena!
What's happened?
They killed the boy.